&gt；&gt；Kyle：我想谈谈，一种不需要打字的方式
&gt;&gt; Kyle: I'd like to talk about, a way of doing typing that doesn't require
我们限制我们的编码风格只是为了完成类型感知的连接。
us to limit our coding style just to accomplish type-aware linting.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：顺便说一下，缺少运行时行为是一件大事。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: The lack of runtime behavior by the way, is a big deal.
也许我应该早点做个更大的交易。
Maybe I should've made a bigger deal about this earlier.
但是获得断言的方法或者
But the idea that the way to get assertions or
保证您的代码行为类似于键入脚本和
guarantees about your codes behavior in something like Typescript and
流程就是你必须改变你通常会做的事情
Flow is that you necessarily have to change what you would normally do
关于你的编码，这样编译器就会明白。
about your coding so that the things that are obvious are obvious to the compiler.
我确实认为你的类型很重要，但这是有区别的
I do think it's important for your types to be obvious, but there is a difference
在让代码的读者看起来很明显和
between making something obvious to the reader of the code and
让电脑看到一些显而易见的东西。
making something obvious to the computer.
那些是不同的，我们把它们混为一谈。
Those are different, and we kind of conflate those two.
所以本质上，完整的，
So essentially, the complete,
在运行时，打字脚本不可能使您受益。
that there's no way that TypeScript could benefit you in the run time.
您获得的所有好处都是在编译时和
All the benefit that you got was at compile time and
他们承认的是没有任何类型脚本的JavaScript。
what they admitted was JavaScript that didn't have any type script-ishness to it.
所以这意味着要获得所有的好处，你真的必须改变
So that means that to get all of that benefit, you really have to change
你所做的，我认为你把它变成的不太像JavaScript。
what you do, and I think that what you change it into is less like JavaScript.
那么这个替代方案会是什么样子呢？
So what would this alternative look like?
嗯，我已经玩了几个星期，或者一个月，一个月
Well, I've been playing around for the last several weeks, or month, a month and
一半，我一直在玩弄一个关于类型感知的Linter的想法，我
a half, I've been playing around with an idea for a type-aware linter that I
Trust包含了JavaScript的打字系统是关于什么的。
believe embraces what JavaScript's typing system is about.
这给了我们更多的工具，给了我们更多的信心，但是
That gives us more tooling, gives us more confidence, but
不会试图将JavaScript改变成它不是的东西。
doesn't try to change JavaScript into something it's not.
这个项目叫做TypL。
That project is called TypL.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：还没有关于这个的文档，所以如果你去回购，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: There's no documentation on this yet, so if you go to the repo,
您将看到有一堆代码和一堆测试，但没有文档。
you'll see that there's a bunch of code and a bunch of tests and no documentation.
这仍然是阿尔法，我们有一系列的问题，我们正在追踪1.0，
This is still alpha, we have a set of issues that we're tracking towards a 1.0,
我希望很快就会发生。
which I hope will happen fairly soon.
所以你可以提前看到这个项目的运行情况，或者
So you're getting an early sneak peek of this project in action, or
在它开始运行之前，你可以提前看到它。
before it's in action, you're getting an early sneak peek of it.
但在我展示一些代码示例之前，
But before I even show you some code examples,
我想谈谈我的动机。
I wanna talk about my motivations.
从这个缺点列表中，我将如何设计一个我认为更适合类型感知的Linter
From that list of cons, how would I design a type-aware linter that I think goes more
用JavaScript的颗粒？
with the grain of JavaScript?
所以第一，我认为我们只需要标准的JavaScripts语法，并且
So number one, I think we need only standard JavaScripts syntax, and
我的意思不只是代码注释。
I don't mean just code comments.
我的意思是，我们需要能够以这种方式接受JavaScript，
I mean we need to be able to embrace just JavaScript that way,
我们防止自己被某种生态系统锁住。
we prevent ourselves from having a sort of ecosystem lock in.
第二，我认为我们既有编译器组件，又有编译器组件，这一点很关键
Number two, I think it's critical that we have both a compiler component and
运行时组件。
a runtime component.
我的意思是运行时组件，
By runtime component I mean,
您所提供的代码中可能存在一些运行时断言，
that there are runtime assertions that could exist in the code that you ship,
这将断言一些事情，并让你知道是否有问题。
and that would assert things and let you know if there were problems.
因为我认为扭曲我们的编码风格对我们来说是不健康的
Because I don't think it's healthy for us to contort our coding styles just so
我们只能从编译器中获取它们。
that we can only get them from the compiler.
但这也很关键
But this is also critical,
您应该可以选择使用其中一个或同时使用两个。
you should have the option of using one of the other or both.
您不应该使用必须具有编译器或
You should not have to use the system that has to have a compiler or
必须有一个运行时，你应该有这个选项。
has to have a runtime you should have that option.
如果你说，听着，我只想要编译器，而不是运行时，
And if you said, listen, I only want the compiler, not the runtime,
这应该是一个选择。
that ought to be an option.
如果你说，我只想要运行时而不是编译器，
If you said, I only want the runtime and not the compiler,
这应该是一个选择。
that ought to be an option.
今天存在的系统并没有给你任何选择。
The systems that exist today don't really give you any choices along that.
这就是TypL的强大动机。
So that was a strong motivation for TypL.
第三，在ESLint的风格中，我希望一切都是可配置的。
Number three, in the style of ESLint I want everything configurable.
所以TypL的工作方式就是抱怨所有的事情。
So the way TypL works is that it complains about everything.
然后你告诉它你不想看到什么抱怨。
And then you tell it what complaints you don't wanna see.
所以它会抱怨所有打字和流动的东西，以及所有这些东西
So it will complain about all the things that Typescript and Flow and all them
会抱怨和一堆他们没有抱怨的东西然后
would complain about and a bunch of stuff that they don't complain about and then
你可以根据这些偏好来决定哪些错误对你有用。
you get to decide with those preferences which of those errors is useful to you.
它让我们细粒度地说，我想让双等号做
And it gets us fine-grained to saying I want to allow double equals to do
例如，字符串和数字，但没有其他内容。
strings and numbers but nothing else, for example.
您有该级别的控制来自定义此对象的行为以提供帮助
You have that level of control to customize the behavior of this to help
你而不是强迫你做一些不起作用的事情。
you instead of forcing you to do something that doesn't work.
第四，重点从静态类型为主的思想转移
Number four, the focus shifts from this idea of static typing as the main
设计目标是更多关于推断或注释值的内容。
design goal to more about inferring or annotating the values.
换句话说，它包含值类型而不是变量类型。
In other words, it embraces value types instead of variable types.
很快你就会在代码中看到这意味着什么。
And you'll see in the code in just a moment what that means.
当然，您可以选择省略所有这些静态键入错误
Optionally of course, you can have all those static typing errors being omitted
如果这些是你想看的。
if those are ones that you wanna see.
我不会打开那个选项，但是
I'm not gonna have that option turned on but
我会建立一个工具，它有它的情况下，这是你想看到的东西。
I'm gonna build a tool that has it in case that's something that you wanna see.
跟我来？
Follow me?
最后，这里的设计目标是，我想使用JavaScript的颗粒和
And lastly the design goal here is that I wanna go with the grain of JavaScript and
不是反对。
not against it.
我不是想做一个不同的JavaScript。
I'm not trying to make a different JavaScript.
我正在尝试改进我们使用JavaScript的内容。
I'm trying to improve what we have with JavaScript.
所以，从你从流中得到的相同的例子开始
So, starting out as the same example as you got from the Flow and
打字稿示例。
Typescript example.
你可以定义一个变量，如果你在上面配置了选项，它将
You can define a variable and if you have the option configured on it's gonna
抱怨你的静态类型。
complain at you about your static type.
它会说嘿，你分配了一个字符串，现在你分配了一个对象
It's gonna say hey, you assigned a string, and now you're assigning an object and
那是个错误。
that's an error.
因此，您可以选择像过去一样获得该错误。
So you have the option of getting that error just like you did in the past.
它在做推论，它是在推断你给老师分配了一个字符串，然后
It's doing the inference, it's inferring that you assigned a string to teacher, and
那么就推断出你在分配一个对象。
then it's inferring that you're assigning an object.
所以在基本情况下，非常相似，
So in the base case, it's very similar,
在这方面，它是从推理中建立起来的。
in terms of it's building from inference up into it.
但这就是事情开始分道扬镳的地方，
But this is where things start to diverge,
因为如果你想要有这样的错误，但你只想有那些
because if you want to have those sorts of errors, but you only wanna have those
例如，当您说出类型是什么而不是当它推断它时，就会出现错误。
errors when you've said what the type is and not when it inferred it, for example.
所以，让我们说，不要向我抱怨那些推论，但是
So, let's say don't complain to me about those inferences but
当我违反类型注释时，一定要向我抱怨
do complain at me when I violate the type annotations that
我已经做过了，当我对它更加明确的时候。
I've done when I've been more explicit about it.
因此，如果您想要注释类似于字符串Kyle的内容，它看起来是这样的
So here's what it looks like if you wanna annotate something like that string Kyle
你想明确地说那是一个字符串。
you wanna explicitly say that's a string.
你把这个东西放在它前面，就像你在这里看到的一样。
You put, as you can see here, this thing in front of it.
现在，它实际上仍然是标准JavaScript，因为它是一个模板标记。
Now that is actually still standard JavaScript because that is a template tag.
这完全是标准的JavaScript，但它是一个模板标记。
That's entirely standard JavaScript, but it's a template tag.
TypL将使用该模板标记的名称来表示，好的，
And TypL is going to use the name of that template tag to say, okay,
你告诉我你希望这个值被解释为一个字符串。
you're telling me that you want this value to be interpreted as a string.
如果你使用不同的类型，比如数字，后面的东西
If you use a different type like number for example, the thing that's in the back
勾号引用swill将以该形式解释，因此它将显示为42或诸如此类。
tick quote swill be interpreted in that form, so it would say 42 or whatever.
在这里，我是说，我希望老师被解释为拿着琴弦凯尔。
Here I'm saying I want teacher to be interpreted as holding the string Kyle.
注意到一些事情，
And notice something,
这是立即开始的，已经不同于流
that this is immediately off the bat already different from Flow and
TypeScript，因为在这里，我将注释Object属性中的值。
Typescript, because here, I am gonna annotate the value in an object property.
我不需要为这种对象创建一个完整的类型
I don't need to go create a whole type for this kind of object
说明name属性是字符串，我正在注释值本身。
that says that name properties are strings, I'm annotating the value itself.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：如果您愿意，这可以隐含到属性或变量中。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And that can be implied to properties or variables if you want it to.
但我没有必要去创建另一个类型来赋予它该类型
But it's not necessary that I go create another type to give it that type
信息。
information.
所以你想把它想得更像是你对所有价值的地方的注解
So you wanna think about it more like your annotating all the places that values and
表达式出现，而不是注释变量上的类型。
expressions occur rather than annotating the types on your variables.
&GT；&GT；Kyle：因为我认为这就是我们所有的问题。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Because that's I think were we have all our problems.
我们所有的价值观和表达方式都混在一起了。
Where all of our values and expressions get all mixed up.
我不认为我们的变量被重新分配时会有那么多的问题。
I don't think we have as many problems with our variables getting reassigned.
您也可以更加明确，即使在这种特殊情况下，您可以标记
You can also be more explicit even in this particular case you could tag
那东西作为一个物体。
that thing as an object.
您会注意到，我仍然将object literal放在模板中
You'll notice that I still have the object literal dropped inside of a template
标记表达式。
tagged expression.
但现在这是说它绝对是一个物体，
But this is now saying it's absolutely an object,
不要只是猜测它是一个对象，它绝对是一个对象。
don't just guess that it's an object, it's absolutely an object.
因此，将其放入错误领域的原因是标记类型冲突
So that would put it into the realm of the error is from tagged type violation
与推断的类型冲突相反。
as opposed to an inferred type violation.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：这里我是说这个对象的年龄属性，
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Here I'm saying that the age property on this object,
现在可以容纳整数42。
is at the moment gonna hold integer 42.
所以在TypL中，你可以区分数字，
So in TypL, you can make distinctions between numbers,
整数、有限值和大NS。
integers, finite values, and big Ns.
所以不只有一种数字类型，实际上你有四种数字类型。
So there's not just one number type, you have four number types actually.
重要的是，在这里，我要说的是，无论学生的年龄来自哪里，
And importantly, down here, I am saying wherever student.age comes from,
我基本上是在断言它必须是一个数字。
I'm essentially asserting that it has to be a number.
所以如果Student.age来自某个地方，并且它不是一个数字，
So if student.age comes from somewhere and it's not a number,
这将是一个错误。
this is going to be an error.
如果编译器能找出Student.age，那么它要么是编译器错误，要么是编译器错误
It will either be a compiler error, if the compiler can figure out that student.age
不会是一个数字，否则它将是一个运行时错误，如果它不能算出它的话。
is not gonna be a number or it will be a runtime error if it can't figure it out.
但无论哪种方式，我本质上都是在我的值和
But either way, I'm essentially doing assertions in-line in my values and
表达式。
expressions.
说，这个东西必须是一个数字，这个东西必须是一个整数。
Saying, this thing has to be a number, this thing has to be an integer.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：您仍然可以使用相同的样式来处理您的
&gt;&gt; Kyle: You can use the same style still to deal with the type signatures on your
函数。
functions.
所以在这里，我有一个默认值表达式，
So here, I have a default value expression,
我重载它以允许我为这个函数做类型签名。
which I'm overloading to allow me to do a type signature for this function.
我是说StudentRec应该被假设为这个对象。
I'm saying that studentRec should be assumed to be this object.
现在，我可以用一个标记来注释它来表示Object，但是
Now, I could've annotated it with a tag to say object, but
我只是在做一个物体。
here I'm just making an object.
所以它将推断StudentRec需要是一个有名称的对象，并且
So it's gonna infer that studentRec needs to be an object with a name and
名称必须解释为字符串。
name has to be interpreted as a string.
所有这些仍然是完全标准的有效JavaScript，并且
All of this is still totally standard valid JavaScript, and
如果您将此代码发送到浏览器，则所有代码都将运行。
if you shipped this code to a browser it would all run.
它可能不会做它在编译阶段会做的所有相同的事情，
It may not do all of the same things that it would at the compile stage,
但它都会运行和编译。
but it would all run and compile.
这样编译器就可以接收到这些信息并
So the compiler can pick up on that information and
说好的，这很酷，你想要一个拥有一个字符串的name属性的对象。
say okay that's cool you want an object with a name property that holds a string.
这意味着当我返回StudentrRec.name时，我知道我正在返回
Which means that when I return studentrRec.name I know that I'm returning
一根绳子。
a string.
而且因为我知道我返回的是一个字符串，当我赋值时，它就在底部，
And because I know I'm returning a string, down here at the bottom when I assign it,
现在我可以暗示学生姓名将是一个字符串。
now I can imply that the for student name is gonna be a string.
所以你可以从打印稿中得到的所有相同的东西，但是如果你比较
So all of the same things that you could get out of Typescript, but if you compare
在此示例之前，我不需要进行所有这些额外的工作来设置自定义
this example before I didn't need to go to all of this extra work to set up a custom
键入以提供该信息，因为我将键入放在值本身上。
type to give you that information because I put the typing on the values themselves.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：我们可以对传入的内容做出所有相同类型的断言
&gt;&gt; Kyle: We can make all the same kinds of assertions about what gets passed into
函数，它们返回什么，
functions, what gets returned from them,
无论它们是推断的还是标记的。
whether they are inferred or whether they are tagged.
顺便说一下，这些类型签名是持久的，也可以是一致的。
And by the way, those type signatures are persistent and can also be in line.
所以在这里，我在注释一个回调类型签名。
So here, I am annotating a callback type signature.
on record函数是一个回调函数，但是
The on record function is a callback, but
我是说它必须符合这个特定的函数签名。
I am saying that it must fit this particular function signature.
因此该函数意味着它必须接收
So that function means that it has to receive
一个具有Name属性的对象，该属性是一个字符串，并且
an object that has a name property that's a string and
该函数必须返回void，基本上是未定义的类型。
the function has to return the void basically the undefined type.
所以这是一个内联签名。
So that's an inline signature.
但请注意，这里发生的情况是，我可以将一个函数分配给另一个函数
But notice what happens down here is that I can assign a function to another
变量，并且打印名称的类型签名是持久的，因此当我传入它时
variable and the type signature of print name is persistent so when I pass it in
作为回调，它与第3行所需的类型签名匹配。
as a callback it gets matched to the type signature that is required from line 3.
所以所有那些你期望从打字稿或流程中得到的东西，
So all those same things that you would expect out of a Typescript or a Flow,
我们在做同样的事情，
we're doing those same sorts of things here,
只是我们在数值上而不是容器上做。
it's just we're doing them on the values instead of on the containers.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：在我一直关注的推理方面有很多改进
&gt;&gt; Kyle: A lot of improvements on the inferencing that I've been focusing
最近。
on recently.
这是一个特别有趣的例子，因为这
This is a particularly interesting example because this
是打字稿和流程不能处理的情况。
is a case that TypeScript and Flow don't handle.
也许他们最终会的但是
Maybe they will eventually but
在这种特殊情况下，他们目前没有做任何事情。
they currently do not do anything in this particular case.
所以看起来是一个非常简单的例子，但是
So looks like a pretty simple example but
这里的复杂性比你可能意识到的要多。
there's more complexity here than you might realize.
所以第一，我们在前面的代码中有一个函数调用，我们所依赖的
So number one, we have a function call earlier in the code we're relying
在函数提升时。
upon a function hoisting.
我们在代码中有一个比我们看到的那个函数更早的函数调用。
We have a function call earlier in the code than where we've seen that function.
因此，我们不能真正验证这是否正确，根据
So we can't really validate whether this is correct according to
签名与否。
the signature or not.
所以我们至少要有一些第二次通行证，而且
So we're at least gonna have to have some sort of second pass, and
TypL具有这种多遍推理。
TypL has this multi-pass inferencing.
除了具有多遍推理外，当我们到达函数时
In addition to having multi-pass inferencing, when we get to the function
我们看到该参数没有任何定义的名称。
we see that the parameter does not have any defined name on it.
所以我们要做的是推断
So what we're going to do is infer that
这是int类型，因为我们传入的是int。
this of type int because we are passing in an int.
所以我们要从呼号推断函数签名。
So we're gonna infer the function signature from the call sign.
所以我们已经看到了这个呼叫地点，当我们到达这里时，
So we have already seen this call site, and when we get here,
我们会说啊哈，我记得你之前考了3分，
we are gonna say ah-ha, I remember that you passed in a 3 earlier,
所以现在我们要推断num是一个整数。
so now we're gonna infer that num is an integer.
因为我们知道num是一个整数，所以我们现在知道这个函数的返回值是什么
And because we know num is an integer, we now know what the return value of this
函数是，因为有一个带有该变量的RETURN语句。
function is, because there's a return statement with that variable.
所以当我们做第二遍时，我们现在知道Gimme会回来
So when we do our second pass through, we now know that gimme is going to return
一个整数，因为它传入并返回一个整数。
an integer, because it passed in and returned an integer.
所以现在我们可以将整数类型应用于3，并且
So now we can apply the type integer to 3, and
现在我们可以抱怨您添加了一个字符串和一个整数。
now we can complain that you're adding a string and an integer.
所以这就是正在发生的多遍推理，
So there's this multi-pass inferencing that's happening,
这花了几个星期的工作才使它起作用。
and this took several weeks of work to make it work.
但是如果你在类似于打字稿或流程的东西中尝试相同的代码示例，
But if you try that same code example in something like TypeScript or Flow,
他们只是推断出任何错误，而不报告错误。
they just infer any and don't report an error.
所以这是一个例子，我认为，TypL之所以闪耀，是因为它专注于价值
So this is an example, I think, where TypL shines because it focuses on the value
类型而不是变量。
types rather than on the variables.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：[咳嗽]编译器与运行时。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: [COUGH] Compiler versus runtime.
正如我所说的，编译器将尝试找出它所能做的一切，如果您
As I said, the compiler will try to figure out everything that it can, if you're
当然，使用编译器，它会尝试找出它所能做的一切。
using the compiler, of course, it'll try to figure out everything that it can.
但是如果它能找出一些东西，它就会从代码中删除那些东西，所以
But if it can figure something out, it removes that stuff from the code, so
它不会降低运行时的负担。
it's not gonna burden down the runtime.
但是，它不能解决的任何地方，它都会保留运行时断言。
But any place that it can't figure it out, it leaves the runtime assertions in place.
所以在这个代码示例中，我们在这里输入了一组参数，
So in this code example we've got a set of parameters here that are typed,
我们说name是一个字符串，topic是一个默认为空的字符串，
we're saying name is a string, topic is a string that is defaulted to empty,
count是一个整数，默认为0。
count is an integer that is defaulted to 0.
所以这些都是编译器会注意到的事情，然后说好的，我知道
So those are things that the compiler would pick up on, and say okay I know
关于函数签名，我需要验证那个函数签名。
about the function signature, and I need to validate that function signature.
但是将运往生产的是一组减少的这一组，因为
But what would ship to production is a reduced set of this because there
是我们已经知道可以在编译时验证它的一些地方。
are some places where we already know that we can validate it at compile time.
例如，第9行和第10行，
For example, lines 9 and 10,
我们已经知道这些是字符串，在运行时没有什么可以改变这一点。
we already know that those are strings nothing at runtime could change that.
所以我们可以在编译时验证这些内容
So we can validate that stuff at compile time and
然后删除它们，这样它们就不会给代码和运行时带来负担。
then remove those so they don't burden down the code and the runtime.
因此，这个编译器所做的就是重新编写这个代码，使其看起来像这样。
So, what this compiler would do is rework this code to look like this.
现在您可以看到，在第2、3和4行中，我们仍然使用默认的参数
So now you see on lines 2, 3, and 4 we still have our parameters with our default
值，但是现在我们在代码中有了这些类型断言。
values in them, but now we have those type assertions in line in the code.
因此我们将在运行时保证每次调用此函数时，
So we are gonna guarantee at runtime that every time this function gets called,
您总是为前两个传入一个字符串，为第二个传入一个整数。
you always pass in a string for the first two and an integer for the second one.
其工作方式是，这些标记函数是实际的标记函数，
The way that works is that those tag functions are actual tag functions that
编译器包含在运行时中。
the compiler includes with the runtime.
并且它们在运行时验证您传入的内容。
And they validate at runtime, what you've passed in.
&gt；&gt；kyle：我们已经移除了老师和
&gt;&gt; Kyle: And we've removed the teacher and
研讨会第10行和第11行的断言。
the workshop assertions on lines 10 and 11.
我们在第13行的断言中留下了，因为在这里我们有一个表达式和
We left in the assertion on line 13 because here we have an expression and
我们需要验证实际上进来的是一个数字。
we need to verify that what is in fact coming in is actually a number.
这实际上是一个整数，因为它可以是NaN，也可以是无穷大
That is actually an integer cuz it could be a nan or it could be infinity and
那些不是整数。
those are not integers.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：所以这只是一个快速的简短的一瞥。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: So that's just a quick brief glimpse of that.
我展示的每一样东西，或者我展示给你的几乎所有东西都已经起作用了
Everything that I showed, or most everything that I showed you already works
代码，但这些都没有记录或发布。
with the code, but none of this is documented or released.
如果你想玩它，你可以看看那个回购。
If you wanna play around with it, you can check out that repo.
我希望在接下来的几周内我们会有一个1.0版本
I'm hoping that sometime within the next few weeks that we will have a 1.0 release
然后我们还想做更多的事情。
of that, and then there's a lot more that we want to do.
但我认为这就是JavaScript的打字系统和
But that's what I think embraces JavaScript's typing system and
使它更好，而不是试图重新连接到不同的DNA。
makes it better rather than trying to rewire to a different DNA.Ç